そりゃあ あれだ➡
はい ずばり答えよう！
１着しか
服を持っていないんですか？｣
いろいろと 面倒くさいんだよ｡
実は 同じ着物を
４着 持っていて➡
というわけで 大西
廊下に立ってなさい！
(銀時)え～… ﾍﾟﾝﾈｰﾑ くたばれ
大西さんからの質問｡
｢銀さんは
いつも 同じ着物を着ていますが➡
それを洗って 着回しているんだ｡
主役が ころころ衣装 変わったら
紛らわしいから｡
えっ？ なんで 同じのを
４着も持ってるかって？
だいたいｱﾆﾒは 毎回 服変えると
設定 作ったり➡
ﾙﾊﾟﾝとかだって ほら いっつも
同じｼﾞｬｹｯﾄを着てるだろ？
["Tell us, Ginpachi Sensei"]
Tell us,
Ginpachi Sensei.
[Question & Answers - Ginpachi Sakata]
Well, this question is from someone pen-named, "Go to hell, Onishi-san."
Gin-san always wears the same kimono. Does he only have one outfit?
The answer is...
In fact, he has four of the same kimonos, and he washes and wears them in turns.
What? Why does he have four of the same kimono?
You know... Because it's confusing if the main character changes his costume a lot.
Lupin the 3rd always wears the same jacket, you know.
Besides, in anime, if the costume is different every episode, you need to draw up a new setting and stuff!
It's a pain in the ass!
So, Onishi, go stand in the hallway!
[And so we decided to go full out and change their looks for this episode.]
[Please enjoy the summer fashion
for the Odd Jobs family.]
(ｾﾐの鳴き声)
(ﾊﾟﾁﾝｺの音)
[Pachinko Jumbo]
(自転車のﾍﾞﾙの音)
(男の子)あっ…！
(泣き声)
Stop crying... I'm not going to come over there! Come over here quickly!
(母親)そんなところで泣いてても
お母さん 行けへんよ！
(母親)はよ来なさい｡
(長谷川)おっ…｡
んっ？ よ… よぅ｡
Hey.
あ… あぁ… ｱﾝﾀも来てたの？
Oh...yeah... You're here, too. What's the matter with you? You're sweating like a pig.
どうした？ すげえ汗だぞ｡
負けたのか？
えっ？
Did you lose?
No.
いや… 今日は暑いな｡
It's hot today.
そういうお前も 汗だくだぞ｡
負けたのか？
You're sweating pretty badly, too. Did you lose?
暑～い！
今日は あっついな おい!!
Hot! It's hot today!
Hey, sun! Take a paid day off, idiot!
太陽！ お前 有休 取れ ﾊﾞｶ野郎!!
そうか…｡
ｵﾚは てっきり冷や汗かと…｡
I see. I thought I had cold sweats.
(男性)あっ…｡
(小銭が落ちる音)
♪♪～
(銀時/長谷川)うぉ～っ!!
んっ？
["Why is the Sea So Salty? Because You City Folk Pee Whenever You Go Swimming!"]
Looks like a guy never comes to any good trying to get rich quick, eh?
(長谷川)人間 やっぱり
楽して儲けようとか➡
そういうことを考えちゃ
いけねえなぁ…｡
Money earned through your own sweat just naturally stays in your hands longer.
汗水 流して 稼いだ金は➡
しぜんと 身から
離れねえもんなんだ｡
なんで あそこで
やめなかったかなぁ…｡
If I had stopped right there...
あそこで やめてりゃ お前…｡
I could've won.
あぁ…
もったいねえことしちまったよ…｡
Why didn't I stop at that point...?
あそこで やめてりゃあ…｡
…人の話 聞いてる？
Are you listening to me?
夢と希望に満ちあふれた
ｶﾞｷの頃のｵﾚが➡
I used to be a hopeful kid with a lot of dreams.
How would that kid feel if he saw me now?
今のｵﾚを見たら
なんて言うだろう…｡
拾ったお金で ｱｲｽをむさぼる
おっさんを見たら…｡
A grown-up snarfing an ice pop he bought with money he scrounged off the street.
If only I had stopped then...
あそこで やめてりゃあ➡
今頃 ﾊﾟﾌｪ食べ放題だったのになぁ｡
I could be having all-you-can-eat parfaits right now... If only I had stopped then...
あそこで やめてりゃあ…｡
人の話 聞いてる？
Are you listening to me?
Oh, Hasagawa-san.
はぁ～ 長谷川さんよ～➡
Have you heard of any easy money-making opportunities around?
どっかに いい儲け話でも
転がってねえもんか？
最近は みんな不景気で
３食 ｱｲｽさ｡
Because of the recession, everyone is eating ice pops for all three meals.
I can't eat ice cream three times a day. I prefer having a snack bar for lunch.
３食は ﾑﾘだな｡
昼に一度 んまい棒を挟みたい｡
Hey, stop...
(女)ちょっと や～だ ﾊﾞｶ～｡
Come on! You said you were going to take me to the beach.
(女)海 連れてってくれるって
言ったじゃ～ん｡
Sounds good. I want to go to the beach.
いいなぁ 海 行きてえなぁ｡
(女)私 もう
水着 買っちゃったのよ～｡
I already bought my swimsuit.
いいなぁ｡ ﾋﾞｷﾆ いいなぁ｡
Sounds good. A bikini sounds really good!
Idiot. If we go to the beach right now, we can't swim.
(男)ﾊﾞ～ｶ～｡
お前 今 海なんていっても
泳げねえよ～｡
なんでも 謎の宇宙生物が
出るらしいんだ｡
I heard that some mysterious space creature might appear.
I don't know if it's a man-eating shark, squid or octopus,
(男)人食いｻﾞﾒだか
ｲｶだか ﾀｺだかしんねえけど➡
危なくて 泳げねえってんで➡
but it's dangerous and people can't swim at the beach.
So they've posted a bounty on the monster.
その 化け物の首に
懸賞金が かけられたらしいぜ｡
やだ～ 怖～い！
Oh, no! How scary!
(長谷川)今年の夏は！
えいりあん 一本釣りだ！
This summer...
...we'll do some pole-and-line fishing for the alien!
What? Who are these people?
(女)なに… この人たち…｡
[Kabukicho Station]
というわけで ｵﾒｴら
気合い入れていくぞ！
So, you guys, let's go for it!
(新八たち)お～っ！
ｵﾚたちはな➡
Yeah!
We're not going there for fun! We're going to fight!
遊びにいくんじゃねえんだよ！
闘いにいくんだよ!!
荒波 砕ける 男の海に➡
We're about to ride the wild waves...
さぁ 漕ぎ出そうって
そのときに…！
なんだ ｵﾒｴら 遠足気分ですか！
You guys look like you're going to a picnic!
｢おやつは 300円まで｣って➡
You're allowed to buy snacks totaling 300 yen.
300 yen is nothing for kids these days!
今の子供は 300円じゃ
何も買えねえんだよ！
わかってんの!? ﾎﾝﾄ!!
Do you understand?!
Captain! You can buy 400 Tasty sticks.
(神楽)隊長！ んまい棒なら
400本 買えるであります！
Really?! I can buy that many?
ええっ ﾏｼﾞ!? そんなに買えるの!?
(新八)神楽ちゃん
無意味に 計算 違うし！
Kagura-chan, your calculation isn't quite right.
長谷川さんも そこで驚かない！
(お妙)新ちゃん｡
And Hasegawa-san, this is not the time to act surprised!
Shin-chan, don't you need to point out Gin-san's outfit?
(お妙)あんなこと言ってる
銀さんの格好は➡
つっこんであげなくていいの？
うるせえなぁ！
Shut up. I didn't expect anything like that.
つっこみなんか
ﾊﾅから期待してないから！
っていうか ｵﾒｴこそ
なんで ここにいるんだよ？
By the way, what are you doing here?
だって 海に行くんでしょう？
I heard you're going to the beach, right?
何度も言わせんなよ この野郎！
Don't make me say that again.
We're going to work!
ｵﾚたちは 仕事しにいくんだよ！
I heard you're going to the beach, right?
だって 海に行くんでしょ？
だからよ…｡
Not again...
Hey, Gin-san, holding nonsensical conversations won't do us any good.
おい 銀さん 無意味に
かみ合わない会話をしてても➡
埒があかねえ｡
とっとと 海へと向かおうや｡
Let's just go to the beach.
誰に 先を越されるか
わかりゃしねえからな｡
I hope nobody will beat us there.
What?! We don't have a car?
(神楽)えぇ～っ！
車じゃないｱﾙか？
(神楽)銀ちゃ～ん｡
Gin-chan!
Where's the money for it?
そんな金 どこにある？
えぇ～｡
What?! It took me all night to make a music tape.
私 徹夜で
ｶｾｯﾄ編集してきたのに…｡
[My Best]
How old are you?
っていうか いくつだよ？
30代 初ﾃﾞｰﾄ 免許取りたての
思い出じゃねえんだからよ～！
It's not like you're going on your first date or getting your first driver's license in your 30s.
ｶｾｯﾄﾃﾞｯｷなんて もう この世に
存在しないってば～｡
Cassette tape players aren't built in cars anymore.
せっかく作ったのに ﾏｲﾍﾞｽﾄ…｡
I worked really hard to make "My Best" tape.
時間がない｡ 急ぐぞ！
って銀さん 切符 切符！
We don't have time. Let's go.
Gin-san! A ticket, a ticket!
We can't even afford to buy a train ticket. Can't you understand?
だから
切符 買う金すらねえんだよ｡
そのくらい 察しろや｡
それじゃあ どうやって…？
Then how can we...?
Ride stealing, ride stealing. We have to cheat on the train fare, uh-huh.
ｷｾﾙｱﾙね ｷｾﾙ！
薩摩の守 ﾀﾀﾞ乗りｱﾙね！
だから 犯罪だろ それ！
But that's a crime! How about buying discount fares at least?
せめて 青春18切符 買おうよ！
We have no choice. We'll take a taxi...
しかたない｡ だったらﾀｸｼｰで…｡
Hey, hey! This man changes his mind in the same breath!
お～い!!
舌の根も乾かないうちに➡
もっと 危険なこと言ってるよ
この人！
How about that? Let's take that for now.
だったら あれでどうだ？
あれで とりあえず 海まで…｡
もう ﾑﾘだよ｡
執行猶予もつかないよ｡
It's impossible. We can't even get probation.
I don't know what to do.
もう 収拾つかないから…｡
(お妙)ﾎﾝﾄにもう 揃いも揃って
世話が焼けるわね｡
Oh, well. You guys are really high-maintenance.
私みたいな常識人がいたことに
感謝なさい｡
You should be thankful someone like me has common sense.
まさか ｵﾒｴ…｡
It can't be... You...
お金 持ってるｱﾙか？
You have money?
Don't worry. My budget is still strapped.
心配しないで｡
いまだに 家計は火の車よ｡
だから お金をかけずに
海に行く方法を探しましょうね｡
So let's find out how we can get to the beach on the cheap.
なんだよ～｡ 偉そうに
たんか切ったわりには➡
You sounded like you had some sort of great idea, but you're suggesting we hitchhike?
普通に ﾋｯﾁﾊｲｸかよ｡
私 知ってるｱﾙ！
I know that! You can stop a car with a sexy wink, right?
お色気や ｳｲﾝｸで
車 止めるﾔﾂｱﾙね！
よっしゃ～！
ｵﾚの太ももが 火を吹くぜ！
All right! My thighs will shoot them down.
やめましょうよ 長谷川さん｡
Stop it, Hasegawa-san. No cars will stop for your hairy legs.
その すね毛じゃ
止まるもんも止まりませんから｡
はぁ～ しかたないわね｡
I have no choice...
まずは 両腕で
頭を挟み込むようにして｡
First, put both hands on your head...
and suck in your stomach...
(お妙)下っ腹に 力を入れて！
前かがみで 胸の谷間を
強調する感じで｡
then stoop forward to show off your ample cleavage...
♪♪～
Go!
行ってこいや おらぁ!!
あぁっ!!
(運転手)うぉっ！
(お妙)はっ！
だっ!!
(長谷川)ぐっ！
(定春)ｱｫ｡
Here we go...
よいしょっと｡
(神楽)ふぅ～｡
Can you turn up the air conditioner?
冷房 強くしてくれるよろし｡
♪♪～
(お妙)すみませんねぇ｡
Thank you. We're so lucky...
でも よかった
たまたま 通り道で｡
...that we happened to be going the same way.
ねえねえ
ｶｾｯﾄかけてよ おっちゃん｡
Hey, can you play my tape?
ｲﾃﾃﾃﾃ！ か… 神楽ちゃん！
Ow! Kagura-chan, you're hurting me! Don't move!
痛いから 動かないで｡
ﾋｻﾞで 傷口 押してるから！
Your knee is pushing into my cut.
なぁ 体 張って
この扱いって どうよ？
Hey, don't you think we should be treated a little better since we stopped the car with our lives?
ていうか 暑っ！ 暑くて くさっ！
ｱﾝﾀ ﾎﾟﾏｰﾄﾞつけすぎだよ｡
It's hot! Hot and stinky! You put in too much pomade!
Play "My Best" now!
Why can't you sit in the front seat, Sister?
早くかけろよ ﾏｲﾍﾞｽﾄ｡
なんで 姉上が助手席なんです？
Hey, driver, can you make it any cooler?
細かいこと気にしちゃﾀﾞﾒよ
新ちゃん｡
Don't worry about the small stuff, Shin-chan.
It stinks! I can't breathe!
(長谷川)くさっ！ 息できねえよ！
うあぁ～ 生温かい液体がぁ～！
Whoa! Warm liquid!
Sadaharu, was that your pee?
定春 ｼｯｺしたｱﾙか？
ﾜﾝ｡
(銀時たち)ああぁ～～っ!!
(長谷川)くせっ！ 窓 開けろ!!
It stinks! O-Open the window!
"My Best"!
ﾏｲﾍﾞｽﾄ～！
冷房！
Air conditioner!
Warm liquid is on my leg!
生温かい液体が 足に～！
(運転手)ひぃっ!!
(銀時たちの どなり声)
(激突音)
(運転手)ひどい…｡
Oh, my goodness...
Man, what a useless car.
んだよ 使えねえ車だな｡
(神楽)ﾎﾝﾄｱﾙよ｡
So true! I can't believe there's a car that can't play a cassette tape these days!
今どき ｶｾｯﾄかけられないなんて
ｸｿｱﾙよ ｸｿ！
That's crap!
それは違うだろ｡
That's not true.
はぁ… せっかく 苦労して
乗せてもらったのに➡
I made a big effort to get a taxi,
but you were all too excited...
みんなが はしゃぐから…｡
You sound like you stopped the car.
まるで 自分が止めたような
言い方だな｡
(ｾﾐの鳴き声)
あ～… どこまで行っても
海なんて ねえじゃねえか｡
Ah. We still haven't arrived at the beach.
I feel like we've at least made it 200 kilometers.
気分的には 少なくとも 200kmは
走破してるんですけど…｡
文句言わずに 歩きなさい｡
Stop complaining and keep walking.
ちなみに
まだ ３kmも歩いてないわよ｡
Just to let you know, we haven't even walked three kilometers yet.
ﾊｧ ﾊｧ…｡
み… 水をください…｡
Give me some water...
水なら 定春の首の樽に
入ってるｱﾙよ｡
There's some water in the barrel attached to Sadaharu's neck.
あ…｡
こ… これは…｡
Th-This is...
Oh, yeah. Raw water isn't healthy, so I made something like this.
(神楽)あぁ 生水は 体に毒だから
飲めないようにしてるｱﾙ｡
I can't drink it...
飲めない…｡
あぁっ！
み… 水をください…｡
G-Give me water...
減量中の ﾎﾞｸｻｰｷﾞｬｸﾞか｡
Why are you talking like a boxer who's begging for a drink of water but needs to make his weight?
こんなとこで やってても
おもしろくも なんともねえぞ｡
暑いときに 暑いって
言ったところで➡
When it's hot, it doesn't do any good to say how hot it is, right?
なんの意味もねえことくらい
わかんねえのか ｵﾒｴはよ｡
そうそう｡
That's right. If he can speak out like that, he's fine.
そのくらいの普通のｺﾒﾝﾄ
出してるなら 余裕でしょ｡
But if he can't speak clearly...
やばいのは こういうときに
ろれつが まわら…｡
いやぁ さすがだね 長谷川さん｡
You're awesome, Hasegawa-san.
男は 倒れるときも前のめりって
どっかの社長も言ってたっけ｡
It reminds me of what the president of some company said:
"A man should lean forward even when falling down."
Burning asphalt... It smells like those cheeks are burning.
♪♪｢焼けたｱｽﾌｧﾙﾄ
へばりついた ほっぺが｣
♪♪｢香ばしいにおいだね｣
暑いよ…｡ ねぇ 助けてよ｡
I'm really hot! Please help me!
Seriously, my cheeks are hot and it smells like something's burning.
ﾎﾝﾄ ほっぺた熱いし 焦げくさいし
動けないんだよ ﾎﾝﾄ…｡
I can't move anymore... Are you listening to me?
(長谷川)人の話 聞いてる？
…あっ 海｡
え…？
Oh, there's the beach!
♪♪～
(みんな)あぁ～…！
ｵﾒｴら 行くぞ！
(みんな)おぅ！
Guys, let's go.
Yeah!
♪♪～
(波の音)
[Danger! Swimming is prohibited!]
(おじさん)あ？ えいりあん退治？
ﾎﾝﾄに来たの？
Oh? An alien hunt? Huh? Someone actually showed up?
Really?
(おじさん)あぁ そう｡
ﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ！ いやぁ 助かるよ｡
This will be a big help!
(おじさん)夏場は
かき入れどきだってのにさぁ➡
Summer time is the busiest season, you know,
and we're not getting any customers because of the alien! We're really in trouble.
あの化け物のせいで 客 全然
入らなくて まいってたのよ～｡
あの～ ひょっとして…｡
Um... Is that...
...you who posted the bounty...?
えいりあんに
懸賞金かけたのって…｡
Right. That's me.
あぁ おじさんだよ おじさん｡
いやぁ～ でも ﾎﾝﾄに
来てくれるとは思わなかったよ｡
But I didn't expect anyone to come.
(おじさん)
おじさんもさぁ 酒の席で➡
I was kind of joking about it over drinks.
ふざけ半分で
発言したことだけに➡
So I never thought somebody would actually come.
まさか ﾎﾝﾄに来てくれるとは…｡
(おじさん)ぐほぉっ！
酒の席で ふざけ半分？
Joking over drinks?! Hey, we're serious about making money for a living.
おじさん こっちは 生活が
かかってるから 真剣なんだよ｡
A man's gotta put his life on the line even when he's joking-
男は 冗談 言うときも 命がけ｡
自分の言葉に
責任をもってもらおう｡
and we're gonna make sure you keep your end of the deal.
Hey, wait! Calm down!
待ってぇ 落ち着いて！
Don't worry! I'll pay you. I have money.
大丈夫 金なら ちゃんと払うから｡
ちゃんと用意してるから！
ｳｿつくんじゃねえよ｡
You liar! Your yakisoba noodles are pathetic.
こんな もっさりした
焼きそばしか焼けないﾔﾂ➡
There's no way a guy like you has any money.
金 持ってるわけないね｡
I bet your life must be one big fried noodle.
どうせ お前の人生も
もっさりしてんだろ｡
ほら 言ってみろよ もっさりって｡
That's right, go ahead and say it - noodle!
はい もっさり｡
Noodle!
(おじさん)ちょっと！ なに
売りもん 勝手に食べてんの!?
Hey! You can't just eat!
You have to pay for it!
Listen, I'm a man of the sea.
おじさんだって
こう見えても 海の男だぞ！
It's true I don't have any money, but I can give you something just as valuable!
金は確かにないが それ相応の品を
礼として出すって！
Hmm... Then I need to see it first.
We'll get rid of the alien after that.
ほぅ…
じゃ 見せてもらおうじゃねえか｡
えいりあん退治は そのあとだ｡
(みんな)うん｡
Right!
[Beach Samurai]
Cool shirt, Gin-san.
ｽﾃｷなｼｬﾂですね 銀さん｡
そうだな｡
Right. If I'd worn this as a teenager, it may have been enough to push my mother to domestic violence.
思春期に
母ちゃんが もし着てたら➡
ﾄﾞﾒｽﾃｨｯｸﾊﾞｲｵﾚﾝｽの
引き金になりそうだな｡
That shirt is
(おじさん)そのｼｬﾂはねぇ
ｳﾁの店員しか➡
rare and not for sale. Only my staff can wear it.
着ることが許されない
非売品の ﾚｱものだよ！
Now you are all fellow men of the sea!
(おじさん)これで ｷﾐたちも
海の男の仲間入りだ！
So release me now! Men of sea don't do this kind of thing!
だから ｵﾚを解放しろ！
海の男は こんなことしないぞ！
Gin-san, what are we going to do now?
銀さん これから どうします？
Well...
そりゃ…｡
(長谷川)やるしかねえだろ｡
We've got no choice but to do it.
やるって 何を？
We have to do what?
You've got a deserted beach,
誰もいない海に
１匹の化け物と ３匹のﾋﾞｰﾁの侍｡
one alien, ..and three beach samurai.
ｵﾚたちが守らずに
誰が この海を守るってんだ？
Who'll protect the beach if we don't?
(長谷川)お前らは
何か落ち込んだとき➡
When you're down, how do you pick yourself up?
どうやって 気を静める？
人間ってのは その立ち直り方で
２種類に大別できるんだ｡
People fall into two categories...depending on how they pick themselves up.
The first kind of person...
(長谷川)１つめは
自分よりも小さなもんを見て➡
comforts himself by seeing somebody who's worse off and thinking,
ｵﾚは まだﾏｼだ と慰めるﾔﾂ｡
"Hey, at least I'm better off than that guy."
２つめは
自分より大きなもんを見て➡
And the second kind of person...
sees a challenge and tries to raise himself to it.
ﾁﾝｹな自分ごと
どこかへ すっ飛ばしてしまうﾔﾂ｡
(長谷川)ｵﾚは ２つめだ｡
I belong to the second group.
Since the olden days, whenever I've gotten into trouble, I always come to the ocean.
昔から ｲﾔなことがあると
よく 海に来た｡
Helps me realize how tiny I am.
己の小ささを知るためにな｡
By the way, I met my first wife, Hatsu, at the ocean.
ちなみに 妻の ﾊﾂと
出会ったのも 海だ｡
What I'm trying to say is, it's like the sea is my textbook and teacher.
(長谷川)わかるか？
海はｵﾚの教科書であり➡
先生であるんだ｡
人は誰でも 心に➡
Everyone has some place in their heart they can fall back on when they need to.
よりどころというものを
もってるのさ｡
たとえ 職を転々としてようが➡
Even if I drift from job to job,
ｵﾚの心は いつもここにある｡
my heart is always here.
そして 仕事ってのは➡
And those jobs are the ways I define myself.
そういった自分の居場所を
守る手段だと思ってる｡
Money doesn't matter. I believe that this job is my calling.
金うんぬんじゃねえ
ｺｲﾂは ｵﾚの天職だ｡
Do you understand my feelings?
わかるか？ この気持…｡
Huh?
あれっ？
本当ですか？ 姉上｡
Is that right, sister?
町内会の方に 話 つけてきました｡
I reached a settlement with the community association.
その えいりあんを倒せば
多少のお礼をするって｡
If we get rid of the alien, they'll give us something in return.
ちょ ちょっ 話 聞い…｡
だったら➡
Hey, please listen to me...
Then we gotta be fired up!
気張ってやるしかねえな｡
ｵ… ｵﾚの気持…｡
M-My feelings...
Let's go.
よし いくぞ！
ええ！
Right!
あぁ…｡
(波の音)
But why do I have to do this?
(おじさん)だからさぁ
なんで こうなんの？
(おじさん)おじさん
なんか悪いことした？
Did I do something wrong?
おじさん ただ 焼きそば
焼いただけじゃないか！
I was just cooking fried noodles!
ふぁ～あ…｡
Give me a break! My legs are wrinkly. Please help!
(おじさん)もう 勘弁してよ～｡
(おじさん)足が
ふやけちゃったよ～｡
(おじさん)しわしわの
ふにゃふにゃじゃ➡
救いがないってば！
I can't catch a thing.
釣れねえな｡
I wonder if it's not in the sea anymore...
もしかしたら もうこの海には
いないんじゃないですかぁ…｡
I don't think so.
(長谷川)いや
そんなことはないぞ｡
ﾔﾂは きっと この海にいる｡
I have a feeling the alien is still in the sea.
ｵﾚには わかる！
I can feel it.
This alien is prepared to fight us. A fight between men.
(長谷川)えいりあんは
ｵﾚたちとの闘いを待っている｡
(長谷川)男の勝負をな！
(長谷川)息詰まる攻防｡
Breathtaking offense and defense.
And...
(長谷川)そして 男のﾛﾏﾝ！
It's about man's romance with the sea!
♪♪～
The alien must be waiting for just the right time!
(長谷川)えいりあんは
そのときがくるのを➡
じっと息を潜めて
待ってるに違いない！
ﾌｰｯ… わかるだろ この気持…｡
You understand how I feel...
Miss, do you understand my feelings?
お嬢さん ｵﾚの気持が
わかってもらえますか？
Yes, I do.
ええ 私は…｡
Oh, thank you, Miss...
ああ… ありがとう お嬢さ…｡
よかったら おひとつどうですか？
Would you like to have one? I made this omelet this morning.
今朝 作ってきたんですよ
卵焼き｡
えっ？ あの…｡
Um...
お腹が空いては
戦もできませんものね｡
You can't fight if you're hungry.
How about another one?
よろしかったら もうひとつ
いかがです？
あっ いや… もう十分で…｡
Um...I've had enough...
お嬢ちゃん わかるか？
Miss, do you understand... how I feel?
ｵﾚの気持…｡
I wish I could swim like them.
いいなぁ みんな泳げて｡
あぁ そうか…｡
I see... You're sensitive to the sun, so you can't go swimming.
お嬢ちゃんは 日の光に弱いから
海水浴もできねえのか｡
でも やめといたほうがいいだろ｡
But it's best you not be out there.
遠慮しなくていいんですよ｡
Don't be shy.
The alien might appear. Are they all right?
えいりあんが
出るかもしれんってのに➡
大丈夫か？ ｱｲﾂら｡
…まっ いいか｡
Oh, well. If they can't listen to a guy's story then they deserve to die.
人の話 聞かんﾔﾂは
死んじまえばいいんだ｡
Must be nice to swim.
いいなぁ みんな泳げて｡
お嬢ちゃん
ちょっと 何するつもり？
Miss? What are you going to do? Where did you find that?
どこで見つけてきたの？ それ｡
Don't want to watch someone else be happy.
他人の幸せ見るくらいなら➡
いっそ壊してしまったほうがﾏｼよ｡
I want to just end their happiness.
みんな！ 逃げて!!
変な子がいるよ～！
Everyone! Run away! This girl is crazy! She's really weird!
この子 絶対 変！ …んっ？
♪♪～
Shoot! It's a double punch!
やっべ！ ﾀﾞﾌﾞﾙﾊﾟﾝﾁだ！
お～い みんな逃げろ～！
Hey, run away, everybody!
Double punch! Two dangers approach you!
(長谷川)ﾀﾞﾌﾞﾙﾊﾟﾝﾁだぁ！
２つの恐怖が 今まさに！
なんだぁ？
ﾀﾞﾌﾞﾙﾊﾟﾝﾂ？
What?!
Double pants? Did he forget his trunks, maybe?
ﾊﾟﾝﾂ忘れてきたんですかね？
Behind you! Shimura, behind you!
後ろぉ！ 志村 後ろぉ!!
お嬢ちゃんも ちょっと待って！
Miss, you'd better wait a bit.
ん？
ひ～っ！
What?
なにを？
(おじさん)ぎゃ～っ！
♪♪～
うわぁあ～っ！
(新八/銀時)ぎゃぁあ～っ！
It's here! Seriously! Like...right here!
出たぁ！ ﾏｼﾞで出た
ﾏｼﾞで出たよ おい！
Agh! I can't make this thing go any faster!
あばばば… 全然ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞが出ねえ！
待て！ 新八 ﾃﾒｴ！
Wait, Shinpachi!
How come you can swim so fast?!
なに すいすい泳いでんの！
It's not like you!
お前らしくな～い！
お前は 何をやってもﾀﾞﾒ！
You're the character who can't do anything right except set up my jokes, right?
つっこみ以外に
何もできねえｷｬﾗのはずだ！
そうだろ!?
いだだだだ！
Ow! My eyes are gonna pop out, my eyes are gonna pop out!
眼ぇ 飛び出すって！
(おじさん)ﾃﾒｴら！
You bastards!
(おじさん)今まで さんざん
やってくれたな！
You made a big mess.
海の男の恐ろしさを
思い知らせてやる！
I'll teach you to fear a man of the sea!
あぁあ！ きたぁ！
なんか 合体してんぞ！
Uohhh! It's coming! They teamed up somehow!
Gin-chan! Shinpachi!
銀ちゃん 新八！
神楽ちゃん➡
Kagura-chan! Hit them back with that rock.
その岩で撃退しなさい｡
うん｡
All right.
(神楽)うおぉお！
Miss, wait, wait, wait! I'm on it!
お嬢ちゃん！ ちょっと
待って待って 待って！
おじちゃん 乗ってるから！
I agree you should throw this rock, but not when I'm on it...
これを投げつけるのは
ｵﾚも賛成だが➡
おじちゃん 乗って… うわぁ～！
せいっ！
There!
(長谷川)ぎゃあぁ～っ！
(長谷川)うぁ～っ！
Oh?
おい これ…｡
Hey, that...
(新八/銀時)うわぁあ～っ！
間違えた…｡
Whoops.
Hey, is everyone all right?
おいっ みんな無事か!?
ﾌｯ… 食いたきゃ 食えよ｡
Eat me if you want....
(長谷川)ﾃﾒｴの胃袋に入って
海を回るのも 悪くねえ｡
I wouldn't mind traveling around the sea inside your stomach.
(長谷川)お前…｡
You...
♪♪～
That's the story.
…というわけよ｡
I think he understood how much I loved the sea.
まっ ｵﾚの海に対する愛情が
伝わったんだろうなぁ｡
It's not about the mind, though.
A man...speaks with his soul.
理屈じゃねえよ 男は｡
魂で語るのが 男だよ｡
His appearance was frightening, but I guess he just wanted to have some fun with us.
あんな身なりだが
ﾔﾂは 悪いﾔﾂじゃねえ｡
ｱｲﾂは きっと ただｵﾚたちと
遊びたかっただけなんだ｡
ｵﾚには わかる｡
I can tell. Because only good people can live in the sea.
海には いいﾔﾂしか
生息してねえからな｡
While you soak in the sea, it washes away all the dirt and scum.
(長谷川)海に浸かってるうちに➡
みんな ｱｸが抜けちまうのさ｡
ｱｸねぇ…｡
...scum...
It looks like the scum stayed on the beach.
なんか ものすごい
ｱｸの強いﾔﾂが➡
写ってるんだが…｡
[Big Hit! Marine Fun Park: Come Play with a Monster!]
Whatever.
ﾍｯ… まっ いっか…｡
There's a ghost in the Shinsengumi headquarters?
[Preview]
Don't be silly!
There's no such thing in this world... Agh! It does exist!
Help me!
The next episode: "Watch Out for Conveyor Belts!"
Conveyor Belts--!
[Who is this red kimono-wearing ghost that appears in the Shinsengumi headquarters every night?]
[Another exciting episode of Gintama coming up next! Get excited!!]
Should I wear a different kimono every once in a while?